Guide to the James F. Lanagan Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
James F. Lanagan papers
1900-1960
SC0662
Lanagan, James F.
0.5 Linear feet
Collection includes Stanford diplomas of Lanagan and Clara Earl, 1900; letters to Lanagan congratulating him after football victories, 1904-05; military papers from his service in World War I, 1918-19, and his letters to Clara while in France, 1918; program from his memorial service, 1937, and letters to Clara about Lanagan from Will Irwin, Ray Lyman Wilbur, and others, 1937-41; clippings on his athletic career and military service; and photographs.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of George H. Knoles, 2002.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
James F. Lanagan earned his A.B. at Stanford University in 1900; in 1902 he married Clara Earl, also a member of the class of 1900. He coached football at Stanford from 1903-1908, as well as baseball in 1906. Lanagan attended Stanford Law School from 1905-1907 and began his law practice in 1908. He was a Major in the U. S. Army during World War I and fought in France. He died in 1937.
Description of the Collection
Collection includes Stanford diplomas of Lanagan and Clara Earl, 1900; letters to Lanagan congratulating him after football victories, 1904-05; military papers from his service in World War I, 1918-19, and his letters to Clara while in France, 1918; program from his memorial service, 1937, and letters to Clara about Lanagan from Will Irwin, Ray Lyman Wilbur, and others, 1937-41; clippings on his athletic career and military service; and photographs.
Access Terms
Irwin, Will, 1873-1948.; Lanagan, Clara Earl.; Lanagan, James F.; Stanford University. Department of Athletics.; Wilbur, Ray L., (Ray Lyman), 1875-1949; Photoprints.; World War, 1914-1918.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Commencement program and diplomas of Lanagan and Clara Earl, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letters to Lanagan with congratulations on football success, 1904-1905 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Lanagan's New Testament carried during World War I, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Military papers (ID card, orders, discharge), 1918-1919 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Lanagan's letters to Clara, April 1918 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letter to Clara from Frank Coffee, 1918 with an account of life in Australia (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Lanagan's navigator's certificate, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Stanford Illustrated Review, Nov. 1928 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letters to Clara regarding Lanagan from Harry A. Deuel, Will Irwin, and Ray L. Wilbur, 1937-1941 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Memorial Service programs and miscellany, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Memorial Book, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous, including a memorial certificate signed by President Lyndon B. Johnson (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Clippings, biographical, 1914-1937 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Clippings, football (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Clippings, football (originals) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Clippings, World War I, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Clippings (not Xeroxed) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Photographs, athletics (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Photographs, general (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Photographs, military (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Photograph, framed (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Photograph, framed (Box 1, Folder 22)